Guide to the Robert Penn Warren Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- January 1995 Acquisition, 1926-1989; 5; 6.67; (16 boxes)
  - Essay by Warren titled Launce and the Low Comedy of Two Gentlemen of Verona, 1928-1928
  - Essay by Warren titled Primitivism and Decadence, undated
  - Correspondence, 1948-1948
  - Correspondence, 1948-1988 (Box 322)
  - Correspondence, 1950-1950; 5 (Box 322)
  - Correspondence, 1950-1950; 5 (Box 323)
  - Correspondence, 1951-1951; 5 (Box 324)
  - Correspondence, 1952-1953; 2 (Box 325)
  - Correspondence, 1953-1985
  - Correspondence, 1983-1985
  - Correspondence, 1988-1989
  - Notebook contents, undated
  - Notebook (empty, contents in previous folder), undated (Box 326)
  - All the King's Men play typescripts, corrected, circa 1948; 2
  - Notes on Cass Mastern, undated
  - Notes on Thomas Jefferson and Lewis and Clark, undated
  - Typescript material, annotated, relating to All the King's Men, undated
  - All the King's Men play typescript, undated
  - Directions and Altitudes typescript, undated (Box 327)
  - Autograph manuscript notes on John Lydgate's Fall of Princes and Mirror for Magistrates, undated
  - Notes on poetry, undated
  - Brother to Dragons play typescript copy, undated
  - The Criticism of Dryden and the Conquest of Granada typescript essay, undated
  - Notes for 16th century course, undated
  - Teaching notes, undated; 3
  - Autograph manuscript notes on J. O. Beauchamp, with an interview from Columbia Broadcasting System on Warren's work, 1939, undated (Box 328)
  - Autograph manuscript notes for World Enough and Time, undated
  - Unidentified notes, undated
  - Typed notes on Elizabethan lyric poetry, undated
  - Typescript essay on John Marston's satires, undated
  - Bibliography of Warren's books, writings of others sent to Warren, and news stories on Warren, 1928-1952
  - Financial documents, 1949-1950
  - Personal files, undated
  - The Ballad of Billie Potts, a libretto by Carl Van Buskirk, with a letter to Warren from Van Buskirk, 1950-1950
  - Notebook, undated (Box 329)
  - Notes on English plays, undated
  - A Study in Decadence: John Webster and Eugene O'Neill essay, 1926-1926
  - Literary notes, 1989, undated; 2
  - Notes on J. O. Beauchamp, undated
  - Notes on J. O. Beauchamp, undated; 4 (Box 330)
  - Notes on Shakespeare, undated; 2
  - Notes on Shakespeare, undated (Box 331)
  - Teaching notebook, undated; 3
  - Printed material, 1947-1988; 5 (Box 332)
    Includes issues of Intellectual Digest (March/April 1971 and September 1972), the Journal de Genève (July 1970), Kettering Review (Fall 1988), Mademoiselle (January 1947), and Modern Fiction Studies (Spring 1960)
  - Manuscript material removed from Robert Penn Warren printed material, 1946-1986
- November 1995 Acquisition, 1960 January 5; 6; 1
  - Autograph letter, signed, to Robert Penn Warren from Denis Devlin, 1960 January 5